Finding Aid for Esquire, Inc. Records 1933-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Esquire, Inc. Records 1933-1977
Esquire, Inc.
85177 Bb/2
Magazine publishing company, principally Esquire magazine, originally edited by Arnold Gingrich, records include editorial files with drafts and manuscripts of articles and some correspondence with authors and some business records.
26 linear feet
2.08 GB
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The records were donated by Esquire, Inc. in 1978. Donor no. 6153
The record group is open for research.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Esquire was founded in 1933 by David A. Smart and William H. Weintraub, publishers, and Arnold Gingrich, editor. Advertised as a magazine for men, Esquire published fiction, travel, and fashion news for an affluent audience. The magazine was immediately successful, and Esquire, Inc. expanded into other areas, including publication of Coronet beginning in 1936. Gingrich attracted many of the most prominent authors in America to Esquire, from Hemingway and Fitzgerald in the 1930s to Styron and Mailer in the 1960s.
By the 1960s the magazine had become less fiction-oriented, and published more investigative reporting by such writers as Tom Wolfe and Philip Nobile. In 1977, after Gingrich's death, Esquire, Inc. sold the magazine, and the editorial files were donated to the Michigan Historical Collections.
The record group has been divided into seven series: Article Files; Sound and the Fury (Letters to the Editor); Story Research File; Correspondence with Authors and Agents; Staff Correspondence; and Assorted Business Files.
The records of Esquire Magazine detail the management and operation of one of the nation's principal literary and current events periodical of the middle decades of the twentieth century. The bulk of the material in the collection consists of research and editorial files for each article published in Esquire.
Although the records contained in the Esquire record group cover only a portion of the magazine's development, they can be used in conjunction with the Arnold Gingrich collection, also on file at the Bentley Historical Library to document one of the most influential publishing ventures of the twentieth century.
Subjects:
Authors, American.; Literature.; Poetry.; Periodicals, Publishing of--New York (N.Y.); Gingrich, Arnold.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Esquire (New York, N.Y.)
Contributors:
Brownmiller, Susan.; Buckley, William F. (William Frank), Jr., 1925-2008.; Church, Frank.; Condon, Richard.; Felker, Clay.; Heston, Charlton.; Hopper, Hedda, 1890-1966.; Lowry, Robert, 1919-1994; Mailer, Norman.; Mauldin, Bill, 1921-2003; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005.; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1899-1977.; O'Hair, Madalyn Murray.; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980.; Powell, Adam Clayton, 1908-1972.; Rabe, David.; Schoenbrun, David.; Schulberg, Budd.; Sheed, Wilfred.; Styron, William, 1925-2006.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968.; Thompson, Hunter S.; Wechsberg, Joseph, 1907-1983; Yorty, Samuel William, 1909-
- Article files
  The Article Files consists of two dated subseries (1933-1959 and 1960-1977), each arranged alphabetically by the name of author or contributor. These subseries represent a consolidation of the magazine's monthly issue files into an alphabetical sequence. The dated subseries files originally contained, in addition to galleys, drafts of published articles, communications with the editors, research and legal department memoranda, and related correspondence. The unique materials have been retained, but the files have been winnowed of most galleys and some photocopies of article drafts, and brought together alphabetically by name of author. The Article Files series also includes a third subseries, which is a sampling of the monthly issue files.
  - 1933-1959
    - Abbott, Tex (Box 1)
    - Abramson, Martin (Box 1)
    - Ade, George (Box 1)
    - Adler, Alfred (Box 1)
    - Aiken, Conrad (Box 1)
    - Albee, George (Box 1)
    - Aldington, Richard (Box 1)
    - Algren, Nelson (Box 1)
    - Angell, Norman (Box 1)
    - Auden, W.H. (Box 1)
    - Bairnsfeather, Bruce (Box 1)
    - Baker, Charles (Box 1)
    - Ballard, Toddhunter (Box 1)
    - Barbusse, Henri (Box 1)
    - Barrett, Pete (Box 1)
    - Beach, Rex (Box 1)
    - Beer, Thomas (Box 1)
    - Behan, Brendan (Box 1)
    - Benet, Stephen Vincent (Box 1)
    - Benet, William Rose (Box 1)
    - Bercovici, Konrad (Box 1)
    - Bercovici, Rion (Box 1)
    - Bessie, Alvah (Box 1)
    - Bocca, Geoffrey, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Bodenheim, Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Bosworth, Allan (Box 1)
    - Bowles, Chester; and Katlowitz, Robert (Box 1)
    - Bradbury, Ray (Box 1)
    - Bradford., Roark (Box 1)
    - Brown, T.K. (Box 1)
    - Bunin, Ivan (Box 1)
    - Busch, Niven (Box 1)
    - Bynner, Witter (Box 1)
    - Caldwell., Erskine, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Callaghan, Morley, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Cary, Joyce, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Cerf, Bennett (Box 1)
    - Churchill, Allan (Box 1)
    - Cobb, Irvin S. (Box 1)
    - Colum, Padraic (Box 1)
    - Cooper, Courtney Ryley (Box 1)
    - Cummings, E.E. (Box 1)
    - Darrow, Clarence (Box 1)
    - De Beauvoir, Simone (Box 1)
    - De Voto, Bernard (Box 1)
    - Di Donato, Pietro (Box 1)
    - Dimnet, Ernest (Box 1)
    - Dos Passos, John, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Dreiser, Theodore (Box 1)
    - Dreiser, Theodore; and Mencken, H.L. (Box 1)
    - Du Bois, Guy Pene (Box 1)
    - Dunsany, Lord, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Durante, Jimmy (Box 1)
    - Duranty, Walter (Box 1)
    - Duvernois, Henri (Box 1)
    - Ellis, Havelock (Box 2)
    - Fallada, Hans (Box 2)
    - Farago, Ladislas (Box 2)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 2)
    - Feikema, Feike (Box 2)
    - Feuchtwanger, Leon (Box 2)
    - Fletcher, John Gould (Box 2)
    - Freuchen, Peter (Box 2)
    - Gainfort, John (Box 2)
    - Gallico, Paul., 27 folders (Box 2)
    - Gentile, Giovanni (Box 2)
    - Glass, Montague (Box 2)
    - Gogarty, Oliver (Box 2)
    - Gorki, Maxim, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Graves, Robert (Box 2)
    - Grayson, Charles (Box 2)
    - Grey, Zane (Box 2)
    - Gunther, John (Box 2)
    - Halper, Albert (Box 2)
    - Hamsun, Knut (Box 2)
    - Hanemann, H.W. (Box 2)
    - Hecht, Ben, 10 folders (Box 2)
    - Heifetz, Jascha (Box 2)
    - Helmers, Peter (Box 2)
    - Hemingway, Les (Box 2)
    - Henagham, James (Box 2)
    - Heth, Edward Harris (Box 2)
    - Hitchcock, Alfred (Box 2)
    - Hobbing, Enno (Box 2)
    - Hough, Henry Beetle (Box 3)
    - Housman, Laurence (Box 3)
    - Hughes, Langston (Box 3)
    - Hughes, Rupert (Box 3)
    - Hunyady, Sandor, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Huxley, Aldous, 25 folders (Box 3)
    - Hynd, Alan, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Ilott, Harold (Box 3)
    - Inge, William (Box 3)
    - Irvin, Wallace (Box 3)
    - Jarrell, Randall (Box 3)
    - Joad, C.E.M. (Box 3)
    - Jones, James (Box 3)
    - Kantor, MacKinlay, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Kent, Rockwell (Box 3)
    - Kersch, Gerald, 19 folders (Box 3)
    - Knight, Eric (Box 3)
    - Komroff, Manuel, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Komroff, Manuel, 9 folders (Box 4)
    - Kreymborg, Alfred (Box 4)
    - La Farge, Oliver, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Lardner, Ring (Box 4)
    - Larsson, Gosta (Box 4)
    - Latzko, Andreas (Box 4)
    - Lawrence, D.H. (Box 4)
    - Lewis, Sinclair (Box 4)
    - Lewisohn, Ludwig (Box 4)
    - Ludwig, Emil (Box 4)
    - McCullers, Carson (Box 4)
    - MacDonald, John D. (Box 4)
    - MacDougall, Michael (Box 4)
    - Macy, Roscoe (Box 4)
    - Maeterlinck, Maurice (Box 4)
    - Mann, Georg (Box 4)
    - Mann, Thomas (Box 4)
    - Marks, Robert W. (Box 4)
    - Martin, Claire (Box 4)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee (Box 4)
    - Maugham, Somerset (Box 4)
    - Maurois, Andre, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Mencken, H.L. (Box 4)
      (see also Dreiser, Theodore; and Mencken, H.L.)
    - Michener, James, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Middleton, Drew (Box 4)
    - Milburn, George (Box 4)
    - Mille, Pierre (Box 4)
    - Miller, Arthur, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Millerand, Alexandre (Box 4)
    - Molnar, Franz (Box 4)
    - Morand, Paul (Box 4)
    - Moravia, Alberto, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Morris, Gouvernor (Box 4)
    - Nadi, Aldo (Box 4)
    - Nitti, Francesco (Box 4)
    - Nury, Ahmed (Box 4)
    - Odlum, Jerome (Box 4)
    - O'Faolain, Sean (Box 4)
    - O'Flaherty, Liam, 7 folders (Box 5)
    - O'Hara, John (Box 5)
    - Paul, Louis, 5 folders (Box 5)
    - Peattie, Donald C. (Box 5)
    - Pegler, Westbrook (Box 5)
    - Peirce, Waldo (Box 5)
    - Perry, George S. (Box 5)
    - Pirandello, Luigi (Box 5)
    - Poling, James W. (Box 5)
    - Pollock, Channing (Box 5)
    - Poneman, P.R. (Box 5)
    - Poole, Ernest (Box 5)
    - Pound, Ezra, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Renard, Maurice (Box 5)
    - Rivera, Diego (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Glyn (Box 5)
    - Runyon, Damon (Box 5)
    - Russell, Bertrand, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Sahl, Mort (Box 5)
    - Salten, Felix (Box 5)
    - Sandrof, Ivan (Box 5)
    - Saroyan, William (Box 5)
    - Sears, William R. (Box 5)
    - Shaw, George Bernard (Box 5)
    - Shaw, Irvin, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Sheean, Vincent (Box 5)
    - Simenon, Georges (Box 5)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 5)
    - Slocombe, George, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Smith, Carleton, 6 folders (Box 5)
    - Smith, H. Allen (Box 6)
    - Smith, Thorne (Box 6)
    - Sosulia, Yefim (Box 6)
    - Steig, Henry Anton (Box 6)
    - Steinbeck, John, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Stephenson, Carl (Box 6)
    - Storm, John (Box 6)
    - Stuart, Jesse, 18 folders (Box 6)
    - Swain, Jonathan (Box 6)
    - Sylvester, Harry (Box 6)
    - Trieschmann, Charles (Box 6)
    - Trotsky, Leon (Box 6)
    - Troyat, Henri (Box 6)
    - Tully, Jim (Box 6)
    - Tunis, John R. (Box 6)
    - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 6)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik (Box 6)
    - Vaughan, Samuel (Box 6)
    - Ware, Edmund (Box 6)
    - Warren, Rubert Penn (Box 6)
    - Wassermann, Jacob (Box 6)
    - Waugh, Alec, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Welles, Orson (Box 6)
    - Werfel, Franz (Box 6)
    - West, Anthony (Box 6)
    - Whitman, Stephen (Box 6)
    - Williams, Tennessee, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Wintle, A.D. (Box 6)
    - Wolfe, Thomas, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Wolfert, Ira (Box 6)
    - Wouk, Herman (Box 6)
    - Yutang, Lin (Box 6)
    - Zara, Louis (Box 6)
    - Zazeela, Herman (Box 6)
    - Zilahy, Lajos (Box 6)
    - Zolotov, Maurice (Box 6)
    - Zweig, Arnold (Box 6)
  - 1960-1977
    - Adams, Charles L. (Box 7)
    - Agee, Philip (Box 7)
    - Alpert, Hollis (Box 7)
    - Appel, Benjamin (Box 7)
    - Armstrong, Louis (Box 7)
    - Asimov, Isaac (Box 7)
    - Astor, Gerry; and Baldwin, James (Box 7)
    - Atwater, James (Box 7)
    - Auden, W.H. (Box 7)
    - Aurthur, Robert A., 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Baez, Joan (Box 7)
    - Bagdikian, Ben H. (Box 7)
    - Bailey, Anthony (Box 7)
    - Baldwin, James (Box 7)
      (see also Astor, Gerry; and Baldwin, James)
    - Baring Gould, William S. (Box 7)
    - Barth, John, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Bartley, Diana (Box 7)
    - Bedford, Sybille (Box 7)
    - Bellow, Saul, 6 folders (Box 7)
    - Benton, Robert; and Newman, David (Box 7)
    - Berendt, John (Box 7)
    - Berendt, John; and Epstein, Edward J. (Box 7)
    - Berger, Thomas (Box 7)
    - Berry, Wendell (Box 7)
    - Bird, Caroline (Box 7)
    - Bishop, Joseph W. (Box 7)
    - Blake, James (Box 7)
    - Bledsoe (Box 7)
    - Bogdanovitch, Peter, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Boll, Heinrich (Box 8)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis (Box 8)
    - Bourjaily, Vance, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Bowles, Paul. (Box 8)
    - Brautigan, Richard, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Brock, Edwin (Box 8)
    - Brown, Barry (Box 8)
    - Brown, Claude; and Calloway, A1 (Box 8)
    - Buckley, William F. (Box 8)
    - Burroughs, William, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Burroughs, William, Jr. (Box 8)
    - "Can You Spot the Sin in this Picture?" (Box 8)
    - Capote, Truman, 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Cassill, R.V. (Box 8)
    - Castaneda, Carlos (Box 8)
    - Cloar, Carroll (Box 8)
    - Cohn, Roy M. (Box 8)
    - Connell, Evan S. (Box 8)
    - Cooper, C.L. (Box 8)
    - Coover, Robert (Box 8)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 8)
    - Davis, Christopher (Box 8)
    - DeLillo, Don (Box 8)
    - DeMille, Agnes (Box 8)
    - Dickinson, Patric (Box 8)
    - Dickey, James, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Dineson, Isak (Box 8)
    - Donleavy, J. P. (Box 8)
    - Dos Passos, John (Box 8)
    - Duerrermatt, Friedrich (Box 8)
    - Dundy, Elaine (Box 8)
    - Dygert, James H. (Box 8)
    - Ebert, Roger (Box 8)
    - Elliott, George (Box 8)
    - Emerson, Gloria (Box 8)
    - Ephron, Nora (Box 9)
    - Ettinger, R.C.W. (Box 9)
    - Exley, Fred (Box 9)
    - Farley, James A. (Box 9)
    - Fast, Howard, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 9)
    - Faust, Irvin (Box 9)
    - Felker, Clay, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Fellini, Federico (Box 9)
    - Felson, Benjamin (Box 9)
    - Fensterwald, Bernard (Box 9)
    - Fiedler, Leslie (Box 9)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott; and Perkins, Maxwell (Box 9)
    - Fleming, Ian (Box 9)
    - Frazier, George (Box 9)
    - Friedman, Bruce Jay, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 9)
    - Gardner, John, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Gilbert, Jack (Box 9)
    - Gingrich, Arnold, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Gleason, Ralph J. (Box 9)
    - Goddard, James (Box 9)
    - "Goodbye to All of You" (Box 9)
    - Gunther, John (Box 9)
    - Guthrie, A.B. (Box 9)
    - Halberstam, David, 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Hannah, Barry, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Hayward, Brooke (Box 10)
    - Hellman, Lillian, 2 folders (Box 10)
      (See also Meehan, Tom; and Hellman, Lillian)
    - Hemingway, Ernest, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Herr, Michael, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Hinckle, Warren J. (Box 10)
    - Holloway, John (Box 10)
    - Honan, William H., 3 folders (Box 10)
    - Hughes, Eileen (Box 10)
    - Huxley, Aldous (Box 10)
    - Inge, William (Box 10)
    - Innes, Michael; and Merric, J.J. (Box 10)
    - Jablonski, Edward (Box 10)
    - Jackson, George (Box 10)
    - Jennings, Paul (Box 10)
    - Jones, James, 3 folders (Box 10)
      (see also, Styron, William; and Jones, James)
    - Kazakov, Yuri (Box 11)
    - Kazan, Elia; and MacLeish, Archibald (Box 11)
    - Keats, John (Box 11)
    - Kelley, William (Box 11)
    - Kempton, Murray (Box 11)
    - Kennedy, Edward M. (Box 11)
    - Koestler, Arthur (Box 11)
    - Kraft, Joseph (Box 11)
    - Lardner, George (Box 11)
    - Lawrenson, Helen (Box 11)
    - Leary, Timothy (Box 11)
    - Leonard, John (Box 11)
    - Lester, Elenore (Box 11)
    - Levitt, Leonard (Box 11)
    - Lindsay, John (Box 11)
    - Linscott, Robert (Box 11)
    - Lyle, David, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - McCarry, Charles (Box 11)
    - Macdonald, Dwight, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - McGovern, George (Box 11)
    - Mahoney, Tom (Box 11)
    - Mailer, Norman, 24 folders (Box 11)
    - Mailer, Norman, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Malamud, Bernard (Box 12)
    - Masterson, Dan (Box 12)
    - Matthiessen, Peter (Box 12)
    - Maurois, Andre (Box 12)
    - Mayer, Martin, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Medelman, John (Box 12)
    - Meehan, Tom; and Hellman, Lillian (Box 12)
    - Mezan, Peter (Box 12)
    - Milford, Nancy (Box 12)
    - Miller, Arthur, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Miller, Merle, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Minnesota Fats (Box 12)
    - "Monty Python's American Diary" (Box 12)
    - Moore, Harold (Box 12)
    - Moore, Marianne (Box 12)
    - Morgan, Neil (Box 12)
    - Morgan, Perry (Box 12)
    - Morgan, Tom (Box 12)
    - Morris, Wright, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Moss, Howard (Box 12)
    - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Muggeridge, Malcolm (Box 13)
    - Murray, Madalyn (Box 13)
    - Nabokov, Vladimir, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Nadel, Gerry, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Newhouse, John (Box 13)
    - Newman, Arnold; Roberts, Steven; Niflis, Michael (Box 13)
    - Nobile, Philip, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Nolen, William (Box 13)
    - Norris, Leslie (Box 13)
    - Novick, Julius (Box 13)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Ober, Harold (Box 13)
    - O'Hara, John (Box 13)
    - Oldenburg, Claes (Box 13)
    - Ostroff, Anthony (Box 13)
    - Ozick, Cynthia (Box 13)
    - Page, Martin (Box 13)
    - Parmentel, Noel E. (Box 14)
    - Pegler, Westbrook (Box 14)
    - "Pill Society" (Box 14)
    - Poirier, Normand (Box 14)
    - Poetry May 1971-September 1977, 47 folders (Box 14)
    - Poetry, miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Rapoport, Roger (Box 14)
    - Renner, Bruce (Box 14)
    - Ricci, Corrado (Box 14)
    - Richler, Mordecai, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Riess, Curt (Box 14)
    - Romm, Ethel G. (Box 14)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 14)
    - Rosenbaum, Ron, 6 folders (Box 14)
    - Ross, Walter (Box 14)
    - Roth, Philip, 5 folders (Box 15)
    - Rudd, Hughes (Box 15)
    - Russell, Robert W. (Box 15)
    - Ryan, John F. (Box 15)
    - Sealburg, Leslie (Box 15)
    - Sabol, Blair (Box 15)
    - Sack, John, 6 folders (Box 15)
    - St. George, Andrew (Box 15)
    - Schickel, Richard (Box 15)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - "Self Portraits", 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Shapiro, Karl (Box 15)
    - Shaw, Arnold (Box 15)
    - Shaw, Bynum (Box 15)
    - Shaw, Irwin (Box 15)
    - Sheed, Wilfrid (Box 15)
    - Sherrill, Robert G. (Box 15)
    - Silverman, Burt a nd Dinnerstein, H. (Box 15)
    - Simic, Charles (Box 15)
    - "Six Smokers--Six Quitters" (Box 15)
    - Smith, H. Allen (Box 15)
    - Sondheim, Stephen (Box 15)
    - Sorrells, Helen (Box 15)
    - Soule, Gardner (Box 16)
    - Southern, Terry, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Stegner, Wallace (Box 16)
    - Steuer, Arthur (Box 16)
    - Stiles, M.B. (Box 16)
    - Stokes, Terry (Box 16)
    - Strout, Richard (Box 16)
    - Stuart, Jesse, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Styron, William, 7 folders (Box 16)
    - Styron, William and Jones, James (Box 16)
    - Swados, Harvey (Box 16)
    - Talese, Gay (Box 16)
    - Thomas, Dylan (Box 16)
    - "Three Letters Home from Mississippi" (Box 16)
    - "Three Misspent Lives" (Box 16)
    - Tillett, Lowell (Box 16)
    - Traver, Robert (Box 16)
    - Tynan, Kenneth (Box 16)
    - Ungar, Sandy (Box 16)
    - Updike, John, 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Vidal, Gore, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 16)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - "Watergate Theories", 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Waugh, Auberon, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Waugh, Evelyn, 3 folders (Box 17)
    - Weinraub, Bernard (Box 17)
    - Weinstein, Allen (Box 17)
    - Wells, Reginald (Box 17)
    - "What Kind of President would John McCormack Make" (Box 17)
    - Willard, Nancy (Box 17)
    - Williams, Carleton (Box 17)
    - Williams, Tennessee, 9 folders (Box 17)
    - Wills, Gary, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Wolfe, Tom, 8 folders (Box 17)
    - Wright, James (Box 17)
    - Yates, Richard (Box 17)
    - Young, Stephen (Box 17)
  - Sample issue manuscript files
    - June 1964-September 1970 (Box 18)
    - June 1964-September 1970 (Box 19)
      (continued)
- The Sound And The Fury (Letters to the Editor)
  The record group also includes letters received by Esquire's letters to the editor column, "The Sound and the Fury," for the years 1959 through 1970. The file is almost complete, but some months are missing.
  - May 1959-June 1966, 41 folders (Box 20)
  - July 1966-December 1967, 19 folders (Box 21)
  - January 1968-June 1969, 18 folders (Box 22)
  - July 1969-June 1970, 12 folders (Box 23)
- Story research file circa 1950-1964
  The Story Research File consists of collected material, proposals, and other information gathered by staff researchers for Esquire and Coronet. These files represent the basis for intended or proposed articles to be published in upcoming issues. This series is dated from around 1950 to 1964.
  - Anthology Introductions, Esquire (Box 23)
  - Arizona and New Mexico Booms (Box 23)
  - Australian Flying Doctors (Box 23)
  - Baths and Bathing (Box 23)
  - Bergman, Ingrid (Box 23)
  - Best Places to Live (Box 23)
  - Books that have Changed Laws (Box 23)
  - Cancer Serum (Box 23)
  - Centenarians (Box 23)
  - Child Stars (Box 23)
  - Childrens' Books (Box 23)
  - College Boy Pranks (Box 23)
  - College Grad Jobs June 1957 (Box 24)
  - College Information (Box 24)
  - Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (Box 24)
  - Conservation (Box 24)
  - Coronet Books (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box 24)
  - Credit, Budget, and Debt Sources (Box 24)
  - Ebony (Box 24)
  - Ellington, Duke (Box 24)
  - Espionage (Box 24)
  - Family Finance (Box 24)
  - Famous People's Summer Jobs (Box 24)
  - Fever (Box 24)
  - Finn Twins (Box 24)
  - Fitzgerald, Zelda (Box 24)
  - Freedom of Information (Box 24)
  - German War Assets (Box 24)
  - Goias, Brazil (Box 24)
  - Group Dental Insurance (Box 24)
  - Hurricanes (Box 24)
  - Insecticides and Herbicides (Box 24)
  - Interviews (Box 24)
  - Ions (Box 24)
  - Jazz (Box 24)
  - Jazz Concert (Box 24)
  - Liquor (Box 24)
  - Little Research Projects June 1956-December 1959, 10 folders (Box 24)
  - Louvre Anecdotes (Box 24)
  - Medical Book Statistics (Box 24)
  - Medical Motion Pictures (Box 24)
  - Medical Use of Hypnosis in Children (Box 24)
  - Miracles (Box 24)
  - National Forgotten Shrines (Box 24)
  - New African Republic (Box 24)
  - Nixon Quotes (Box 24)
  - Novel Heroines (Box 24)
  - Ocracoke Island, North Carolina (Box 24)
  - Organizations Persisting in the Past (Box 25)
  - Orinase (Box 25)
  - Oxford Graduation (Box 25)
  - Palmer, Lilli (Box 25)
  - Perfumes (Box 25)
  - Portland Club (Box 25)
  - Pressure on Doctors (Box 25)
  - "Psychic Energizer" Iproniazide (Box 25)
  - Railroad Quotations (Box 25)
  - Refugees (Box 25)
  - Research Finished (Box 25)
  - Rocky Road of Royalty (Box 25)
  - Roost-No-More (Birds) (Box 25)
  - Royal Jelly (Box 25)
  - Saving Manhattan in Two (Box 25)
  - Scare Propaganda (Box 25)
  - Sex Determination (Box 25)
  - Sexy Women over 35 (Box 25)
  - Signoret, Simone (Box 25)
  - Stack's Psychotherapy on Juvenile Delinquents (Box 25)
  - States are Killing our Cities (Box 25)
  - Symposium, Esquire (Box 25)
  - Talmadge, Herman (Box 25)
  - Triumph Sports Car Rally (Box 25)
  - Turin, Italy (Box 25)
  - TV Could Be Great (Box 25)
  - U.N. Foreign Broadcasts (Box 25)
  - Valli, Alida (Box 25)
  - Esquire Magazine (Box 25)
  - Western United States Quotations (Box 25)
  - What Your Sleeping Habits Tell about Your Personality (Box 25)
  - When Physical Conditions Masquerade as Psychic Symptoms (Box 25)
  - Wines (Box 25)
  - Woman as a Hunter (Box 25)
  - Women Alcoholics (Box 25)
  - Women Stock Buyers (Box 25)
  - Women with Unusual Occupations (Box 25)
  - You (completed through December 1958) (Box 25)
  - Young America (Box 25)
- Correspondence with authors and agents
  Correspondence with Authors and Agents consists of proposals, exchanges between editors and authors over matters of content and style, payment discussions, letters of appreciation, and miscellaneous subjects. This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Arlen, Michael J. (Box 25)
  - Armstrong, Frank (Box 25)
  - A (Miscellaneous) (Box 25)
  - Baker, Charles (Box 25)
  - Beebe, Lucious (Box 25)
  - B (Miscellaneous) (Box 25)
  - Cartoonists (Box 25)
  - Charles-Roux, Edmonde (Box 25)